OSENI OMOKAYODE UTHMAN

Frontend Engineer

+234 7062937325 kayodeoseni@ymail.com GitHub: https://github.com/kaydist Lagos, Nigeria.

SUMMARY

Enthusiastic, goal-driven frontend engineer experienced in developing from scratch and collaborating with design and backend teams to achieve pre-defined objectives. Extensive understanding about software development life cycle such as coding, debugging and maintenance of Web Applications using necessary Technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript, ES6, React JS, Next JS, Gatsby JS, React-Redux
- HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Styled-components, CSS Pre-processor (SCSS)
- Responsive Development
- Web animation (GSAP)
- Version Control (Git)
- Firebase System

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GOZADE LTD

DECEMBER 2021 – JANUARY 2022

Frontend Developer (Contract)

- Developed the Admin dashboard with full user functionality for the organization's new major client using React, React-Bootstrap and SCSS.
- Translated the UX team's new email template design to code using react-html-email.

HOPE

OCTOBER 2021 – NOVEMBER 2021

Frontend Developer (Volunteer)

- Collaborated with the design team in revamping the web app's user interface for a top-notch experience.
- Architected and Developed New Client-Side dashboard.
- Integrated anonymous donator feature to the new Client Side.

HOTELS.NG

AUGUST 2021 – OCTOBER 2021

Frontend Engineer (Intern)

- Led a team of 5 Frontend Engineers in developing the organization's Marketplace App for installation of plugins.
- Improved Client-Client communication speed on organization's Noticeboard App by 3seconds by integration of real time communication.
- Developed custom reusable components using for the organization's Noticeboard Plugin.

EDUCATION

Federal University of Agriculture,

2017 - 2022

Abeokuta

Bachelor of Engineering in Mechatronics Engineering

CERTIFICATION

Grazac Academy Undergraduate Tech

2021

Plan

Frontend Development Track

SOFT SKILLS

- Great Communication skills
- Quick and Adaptive learning
- Time management
- Great Social Relations